(404) 805-5891

Recent Work

WorkN

www.workn.com www.serveture.com

Jan 2017

A website built for a client, Serveture, using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap for responsive design, PHP using Perch for CMS for a blog, and jQuery.

JANUS Oct 2016

www.janus.jt-townsend.com/ https://github.com/paigen11/back-end

A Single page app, built with a team of 4 developers in a mobile-first approach, using Python, Flask, MySQL, and Angular JS to let users organize and store notes. Masonry, a JS library, organizes the notes to add to the UX of each client and **Bootstrap** allowed for **responsive design**.

DC Roasters Sept 2016

www.jt-townsend.com/coffeeSite https://github.com/jttwnsnd/NodeEcommerce

An Ecommerce SPA built with Angular Routes and Cookies, Mongoose, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, a customized API, compiled Jade for the HTML and Sass for the CSS, and uses Stripe for a credit card transaction. A MEAN stack website that provides mock information for the complete user-experience

Zombiez Aug 2016

www.jt-townsend.com/zombiez https://github.com/paigen11/frontend-project

Built with a team of 4 developers utilizing AGILE methodology, this is an interactive map game that makes strong use of Javascript, HTML, CSS, and jQuery along with utilizing the Leaflet API's marker features and functionalities for a canvas-style game that provides various weapons to protect the city of Atlanta from the zombie infestation

Education

Jan 2016 - Present Udemv

Taking the following:

 Udemy Javascript: The Weird Parts (Sept 2016 - Present) • Udemy **Vue 2.0**: The Complete Guide (Nov 2016 - Present) Udemy Modern React & Redux (Dec 2016 - Present) Udemy - AWS Solutions Certification Developer (Jan 2017 - Present)

DigitalCrafts July 2016-October 2016

A 16-week immersive boot camp with MEAN stack, Python, and MySQL

• Front-End Group Project Winner (Zombiez - Aug 2016)

Toni&Guy Hairdressing Academy

Jan 2012 - Oct 2012

A 10 month program giving hands on experience in hairdressing and customer service.

- Student of the Month (May 2012)
- Acquired Certification after 1500hrs of instruction

Honor Academy Jan 2009 – Aug 2011

A self-discipline/leadership program working 31 hrs/wk volunteering for communities and global outreaches.

JT Townsend

(404) 805-5891

Full Stack & Front-End Web Developer

jt.a.townsend@gmail.com

- Intern Graduation Dec 2009
- Graduate Intern Graduation Dec 2010
- Graduate Intern+ Graduation Aug 2011

Previous Work Experience

Serveture

Developer, Contract Jan 2017

- Incorporates mobile view to prevent poor UX.
- Executes designer's mockup to build 2 websites/11 pages in under 60 hrs

DigitalCrafts

Developer-In-Residence, Teacher's Assistant

Nov 2016 – Present

- Assisting instructor in teaching new students, providing solutions that encouraging best practices in programming
- Continual, self-directed instruction in VueJS, ReactJS, ES6, and node.js
- Developing instructional and engaging projects teaching students the code/framework

Toni&Guy @ Town Center Mall

Art Director II, Educator

Aug 2012 – June 2016

- **Motivated coworkers** with work ethic and time management through focusing on clients, technical instruction, and encouraging coworkers to reach goals throughout each day
- Consistently exceeds Daily Salon Revenue Goals on days I managed
- Works in a team environment both as a team member and Team Lead, going from concept through
 actualization of individual creative looks to a cohesive collection for photoshoots. Creates several
 original looks for haircuts and experiments with current trends from research

Honor Academy

Volunteer (Various Positions)

Jan 2009 – Aug 2011

- Works in a call center for 1 year where I set my own time-table of when to complete each project with minimal direction
- 6 months in a traveling production team where I give direction about the overall goal and empower my
 volunteers through letting them make most decisions and supporting them; only adjusting if decisions
 did not support the end goal

Starbucks

Barista

May 2008 – Dec 2008

- MUG Award in July 2008 for Positivity and Quick Learning
- Team collaborations to creatively promote new products